So our game is really coming along.
But this is a header game after all.
And if you play the game, you can see that you don't just have to hit the ball with your head.
You can use any part of your body, and hitting the ball with your head doesn't seem to be the main
element of the game.
So how can we fix this so that only when the ball hits her head does it start to bounce?
We look at our code, this is to be expected has all it's actually doing is sensing the ball is touching
Ben, which is the whole character.
We don't have any code to deal with this, because it's not like we have code that says if it's touching
its head, do something.
But that's fine because we are programmers and we solve problems.
So what could we do?
Well, maybe we could write some code that checks the Y position of the ball and compares it to the
y position of Ben's head, and so on.
And we could maybe eventually get the problem solved like that.
Now, but that would take a whole lot of code and programming.
But it's also about thinking outside the box to find simple solutions to complex problems.
Okay.
So.
All we want our code to do is to check if a touching Ben's head.
Okay, pause the video and think for a moment.
What clever thing could we do to solve this problem?
We want the ball only to bounce off Ben's head.
Pause and think.
Did you come with any good ideas?
Well, here is a gruesome but clever way to do it.
How about this?
We cut off Ben's head.
Okay, now hold on.
You think I sound crazy here?
But hear me out.
If we can have a separate sprite for Ben's head, we can easily check if the ball is only touching the
head.
But of course, we will also need Ben's body so we can have that also as a separate sprite.
But before I cut off Ben's body from his head, I'm going to show you another trick.
We can actually duplicate an entire sprite by just right clicking and hitting duplicate.
Here you can see we now have Ben two.
Okay, so now with that done, we can go to our original bin, go to costumes, and here you can see
we can actually make a lot of adjustments to our character.
But all we need to do is remove the body.
So we can drag and select all this and hit backspace.
And there you go.
Ben is now a floating head.
However, because we duplicated him earlier, we didn't even notice this.
And if we play the game again, look how it works perfectly.
And even if the ball touches the body, it doesn't count.
The one thing I will say, though, is the fact that our Ben two sprite works perfectly is a little
bit unintentional, as we haven't programmed it at all.
And in programming we call this a happy accident.
But the reason it works is because the controls are exactly the same.
So it just follows.
And although this works, which is cool, we still need to change this code because the problem we have
is that if we ever change our original code and Ben for instance, changing the x speed to seven and
minus seven, you can see now things start to get a bit freaky as Ben has a double head.
So instead of this code here, we can get rid of it and replace it with just a go to block.
And we can now select Ben.
Now, if we play our code once more, you will notice that it works.
No problem.
And this is what we call robust code as it is able to adapt to its circumstances.
So we learned some important lessons in this lesson.
Think creatively, but also make sure you code in a resilient way that will work even if things change,
and with time you will learn to do this more and more.